

Pasadena, CA

% jayesswang.com

in @jayesswang

@ @jayesswang

SUMMARY

Creative storyteller, visual strategist, and empathic advocate of user-centered experiences. An inquisitive, perceptive, and adaptable ENTP-A (Myers-Briggs).

Able to leverage an 18-yr work history spanning four industries and three roles. Bilingual with cross-cultural savvy and extensive experience traveling the world since age 13.

DESIGN PROCESS

interviews
focus groups
surveys
competitive analysis
user research
card sorting
info architecture
flow diagrams
sketches
wireframes
rapid prototyping
usability testing
heuristic evaluation

TOOLS

sketch
invision
figma
photoshop
illustrator
dreamweaver
usabilityhub
usertesting
html / css / javascript
git / github
g-suite

LANGUAGE

mandarin chinese

RECENT PROJECTS

WHAT DO YOU MEME?TM MOBILE GAME

Convert a popular tabletop game for adults into a mobile game. Tools include Google Forms, Figma, UsabilityHub, Google Forms, Loom, YouTube.

IW PORTFOLIO

Hand code a responsive portfolio website from scratch and hosting it on GitHub Pages. Tools include Google Forms, Figma, UsabilityHub, Loom, YouTube.

BOXLY

Design an SaaS that allows users to collect, store, and share info all from one place. Tools include Google Forms, Draw.io, Balsamiq, Sketch, InVision, UserTesting.

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE PHOTOGRAPHER | JW PHOTOGRAPHY

2008 - present

Notable clients include: Bebe, Halston, Nordstrom, HauteLook, Ozsale.

GLOBAL CREATIVE PHOTOGRAPHER | FOREVER 21

2013 - 2017

- Shoot models and still life photography for the Global Creative Division, E-commerce, and The Branded Shop.
- Second-in-command to photography supervisor; train new photographers; some duties exceed original job title and description.
- Collaborate across multiple departments; demonstrate corporate diplomacy.

WEB PRODUCER | KAC MEDIA

2010 - 2011

- Start-up work culture with small, nimble, and fluid teams. Resourceful with a limited budget.
- Wear many different hats, jumping in as needed to cover and assist in all production-related tasks from pre- to post-production.
- Produce content, research the story, write scripts, conduct interviews, create video rough drafts in Final Cut Pro.

SENIOR EDITOR | ENVISION MBA

2006 - 2010

- Asia's #1 education consultancy helping MBA applicants tailor their branding & strategy when applying to the top 50 MBA programs worldwide.
- Guide prospective MBA applicants through the application process; lead essay-writing workshops and conduct mock interviews.
- Successfully placed hundreds of students at: INSEAD, HEC Paris, London Business School, Wharton, Sloan, Columbia, Oxford, Haas, and others.

EDUCATION

BLOC.IO | UX DESIGN APPRENTICESHIP

2018

- Certificate in UX Design
- Train in a 52-week apprenticeship under an experienced UX professional.

LOS ANGELES CENTER OF PHOTOGRAPHY

2012

Certificate in Commercial Photography

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA (USC)

2006

B.A. in English & Creative Writing / Minor in Music Business